Guide to the Beatrice Straight papers, [ca. 1925]-1990.
Straight, Beatrice papers, [ca. 1925]-1990
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Beatrice Straight papers, [ca. 1925]-1990.
4496
Beatrice. Straight
c. 16 cubic ft.
Reviews, playbills, letters, scripts, press releases, photographs, and scrapbooks
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Reviews, playbills, letters, scripts, press releases, various photographs, and scrapbooks relating to her life and her acting career.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Actress.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Reviews, playbills, letters, scripts, press releases, various photographs, and scrapbooks relating to her life and her acting career.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Straight, Beatrice.
Subjects:
Actresses.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
COLLECTION ARRANGEMENT
Alphabetical.
SERIES LIST
Series I. Biographical Materials
Series II. Correspondence
General Correspondence
Celebrity correspondence
Family correspondence
Series III. Professional Papers
Background and reference materials
Publicity materials [(B)=Beatrice participated, (P)=Peter Cookson participated]
Scripts [(B) indicates performance/production in which B. Straight took part)]
Proposals
Series IV. Awards/Honors
Series V. Business Materials
Business miscellany
Personal miscellany
Peter Cookson materials
Series VI. Visual Images
Photographs
Drawings
Films
Series VII. Sound Recordings
Audio Taps
78's
Series VIII. Personal Materials
Appointment Books
Miscellaneous personal
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Biographical Materials
  - Beatrice Straight, 1977-1981 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Dorothy Whitney Straight Elmhirst, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Straight-Elmhirst family tree, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Whitney and Straight families, 1980-1983 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Peter Cookson obituaries, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Series II. Correspondence
  - General Correspondence
    - A - Academy of American Poets, 1966-1974 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Academy of Motion Picture Arts and Sciences, 1977-1989 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - The Acting Company, Actors' Enclave - The Actors' Equity Association, 1974-1990 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - The Actors' Fund, 1971-1983 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Adelphi University - Advocates for the Arts; Agency for the Performing Arts, Inc., (APA); APA Repertory Company; Air Time International Inc. - American College Theatre Festival; American National Theatre, 1973-1990 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - American Place Theatre; American Theatre Wing; Association of American Women Playwrights - Association on American Indian Affairs, Inc.; Austin, 1971-1991 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - B - Berkshire-Litchfield Environmental Conservancy Council, Inc. (BLECC), 1966-1991 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Berkshire Theatre Festival, 1979-1991 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Bern - Bombay Cinemas - Boz, 1971-1991 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Br - Peter Brook, International Theatre Institute of the United States, Inc. - Curtis Brown Ltd. - Bu, 1973-1991 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Ca - California Shakespeare Festival - Charles M. Schulz Creative Associates, Chase, 1966-1989 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Chekhov Studios, 1989-1990 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - The Children's Aid Society; Children's Center for Creative Arts - Circle Repertory Company; City Center; City of New York - Classical Theatre Foundation - Cogan Management - College at Purchase - CBS; Columbia University in the City of New York; The Columbus Dispatch - Connecticut Commission on the Arts Awards; Connecticut Theatre Foundation, Inc.; Conner, 1971-1988 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Condolences re Peter Cookson, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 19-20)
    - Cookson - CORD (Congress on Research in Dance) - The Corinthian Theatre, 1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Cornell University, 1976-1990 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Corsair & Co. - Creative Arts Rehabilitation Center, Inc. - Criswell Predicts - Richard Curland, October Productions - Cu, 1975-1990 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - D - De, 1974-1990 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Do - Drama Desk - Dramatic Risks - Du Brock, Studio Arena Theatre; Du Prey; Duffy, 1973-1990 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - East Mid-Manhattan Chamber of Commerce Inc. - Educational Solutions - Ely, Library and Museum of the Performing Arts - Encore - Equity-League Pension Fund; Equity Library Theatre; Equity News; Eye Research Institute of Retina Foundation, 1972-1991 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Faerie Tale Theatre - Family Weekly - The Feminist Press - Films in Review- Fort Worth Art Center; Foster Parents Plan - Harold Freedman Brandt & Brandt; Stanley Friedman - Fryer, 20th Century Fox; Fund for New Priorities in America, 1972-1991 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - G - nf Geria III Filmgesellschaft mbH; Phil Gersh Agency; GeVa On Stage - Karolyn Gould - Group One Television, Inc. - Guardians Theatre Company - Gurian-Sholder Productions, Inc., 1966-1990 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - H - Hambleton, Phoenix Theatre - Walter Hampden-Edwin Booth Theatre Collection and Library - Harper and Row, Publishers, Inc. - Hickman, Porterville Area Shakespearean Guild - High, 1968-1988 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Hill - Historical Society of the Westburys - Housatonic Valley Association, Inc. - Hu, 1938-1990 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - IASTA (Institute for Advanced Studies in the Theatre Arts); Institute of International Education; The Interchange; International Theatre Institute of the United States, Inc. - Is, 1966-1991 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - J - Jeffcoat, Manhattan Theatre Club, Inc.; John Jay College Drama Forum - Junior League Magazine, 1969-1991 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - K - Khokar - Kohner-Levy Agency, 1967-1991 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - L - Lagerfelt - The Lambs - Langdon, 1971-1990 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Langton, 1972-1990 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Larson - League of Theatre Artists, Inc. - Leukemia Society of America, Inc. - Robert Lewis Acting Company; Lexington Conservatory Theatre - Lion Theatre Company - Little, 1971-1988 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Littler, 1963-1965 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Live - Lynn, 1966-1990 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - M - Mahon, 1977-1988 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Mal - Manhattan State Citizens' Group, Inc. - Charles Marowitz - Maslansky/Koenigsberg; Mason & Cumming Productions - Mayfair House, 1971-1990 (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - McCabe - McGraw-Hill Book Company - The Mental Health Association of New York and Bronx Counties, 1977-1988 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Metro-Goldwyn-Mayer - The Met - Midwest Playwrights Laboratory; Millay Colony for the Arts, Inc. - Miller Outdoor Theatre, 1975-1990 (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - Mir - Richard Morse Mime Theatre - Mudge Rose Guthrie Alexander & Mitchell - Museum of the City of New York, 1973-1990 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - National Broadcasting Company; National Endowment for the Arts; National Film Preserve Ltd.; National Repertory Theatre; National Telefilm Associates, Inc.; National Theatre of the Deaf; Navajo Community College, 1959-1979 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - NET (National Educational Television); "Network" (Simcha Productions, Inc.) - The New Dramatists, Inc.; The New Globe Theatre, Inc.; New School for Social Research; New York Philharmonic - The New York Public Library; The New York Quarterly; New York Shakespeare Festival; New York Theatre Review; New Yorkers for Koch, 1971-1990 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Night of 100 Stars - Northwood Institute - Liz Nygaard, the Lynne Gordon show, 1977-1990 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - O - O'Neill Theatre Center; the Open Eye - Outer Critics Circle; Owen, 1966-1977 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Pa - Wm. Packard; Palace Players, Inc. - Performing Arts Group - Pinto, Winokur & Pagano - Pittsburgh Public Theater; Players for the Globe - Poor Murderer Company, 1966-1990 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Pr - Princeton University Press; property; Public Broadcasting Service; Putnam, 1977-1990 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Ra - Readers Repertory Company - The Rehabilitation Institute - Res, 1966-1991 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Ri - Rolling Rep; Eleanor Roosevelt Monument Fund, Inc. - Steve Ross, CBS - Ryan, 1971-1990 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Sa - Saint Clement's - Saint John's University - The Shakespeare Globe Center (North America) Inc. - George Shdanoff - Sherman, E., 1973-1990 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Harold Sherman, 1975-1989 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Shir - Simon Studios; Skowhegan School of Painting and Sculpture - Sotheby's; Southbury Training School; The Friends of George Spelvin - Starlight International; State of New York Department of Agriculture and Markets; State of New York Department of Environmental Conservation - Stau, 1971-1989 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - The Rudolf Steiner School; STE Representation Ltd. - Studio Arena Theatre - Jean Sullivan - Sun Day in New York, 1966-1991 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Arnold Sundgaard, 1973-1988 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Sup - Ingo Swann - Robert Swann, Institute for Community Economics, Inc - Sz, 1973-1990 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - T - Theatre Communications Group, Inc.; Theatre Development Fund; Theatre Hall of Fame; Theatre in the Street; Theatre in a Trunk, Inc.; Theatre Institute at Storm King; The Theatre Museum, Boothbay, Maine; Friends of the Theatre and Museum Collection, The Museum of the City of New York; Theatre Network of Houston; Theatreworks USA - Town Hill School - Twelfth Night Club, 1970-1990 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - U - University of Chicago; University of Wyoming, 1971-1985 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - V - the Village Voice - Vogt, 1972-1990 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - W - Kelly Ann Whalen, Creative Arts Rehabilitation Center, Inc. - William C. Whitney Foundation; Whitney Museum of American Art - Who's Who in the Theatre - The Williamstown Theatre; Williamstown Theatre Festival, 1972-1990 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Yale University; Nicholas Yanni - Young World Foundation, 1971-1980 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Z, 1966-1979 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - No surname: A - K, 1939-1991 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - No surname: L - V, 1966-1989 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Illegible and unidentified correspondents, 1966-1990 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Celebrity correspondence
    - Abraham D. Beame, Theodore Bikel, Jimmy Carter, Greer Garson, Lillian Gish, Alec Guinness, Hal Holbrook, Angela Lansbury, Shirley MacLaine, Laurence Olivier, Peter Sellers, Artie Shaw, Elizabeth Taylor and Robert F. Wagner, Jr., 1960-1989 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Family correspondence
    - Bowater family, 1972-1979 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Nellie (Nello) Von Volkenberg Browne, 1971-1974 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Beatrice Straight Cookson, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Gary Cookson, 1977-1988 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Gary Straight Cookson baby book, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Maurine Cookson to Gary Cookson, n. d. (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Peter Cookson, 1974, n. d. (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Peter W. Cookson, Jr., 1974, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Tony Cookson family, 1979, n. d. (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Brooksie Cookson Copland, 1971-1987 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Sue Elmhirst, 1974-1975 (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - Jessica Padillo, n. d. (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - Lady Daphne Straight, n. d. (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - Michael Straight, 1971-1979, n. d. (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - Whitney Straight, 1951-1977, n. d. (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - Unidentified, n. d. (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - Blank cards and postcards (Box 2, Folder 42)
- Series III. Professional Papers
  - Background and reference materials
    - "Acting for Life," by Felicity Mason with Michael B. Ellner. R.H., n. d. (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - Actors' Enclave, 1987-1988 (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - The Actors' Equity Association, 1978-1980 (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - The Actors' Fund of America, 1977-1979 (Box 2, Folder 46)
    - Edward Albee, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 47)
    - Alley Theatre, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - American College Theatre Festival, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - AFTRA (American Federation of Television and Radio Artists), 1976-1988 (Box 2, Folder 50)
    - Tallulah Bankhead, n. d. (Box 2, Folder 51)
    - Seymour Barab, n. d. (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - Sherie Berk, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 53)
    - Berkshire Public Theatre, 1990-1991 (Box 2, Folder 54)
    - Berkshire Theatre Festival, 1967-1988 (Box 2, Folder 55)
    - Brain/Mind Bulletin, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 56)
    - California Shakespeare Festival, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 57)
    - Martin Casella, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 58)
    - Anton Chekhov, 1990, b. d. (Box 2, Folder 59)
    - Michael Chekhov, 1971-1988 (Box 2, Folder 60)
    - "A Portrait of Misha: The Life and Artistic Accomplishments of Mikhail Alexandrovich Chekhov," by Lendley C. Black, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - "Letters of Anton Chekhov," translated by Michael Henry Heim in collaboration with Simon Karlinsky; Selection, Commentary & Introduction by Simon Karlinsky (volume), 1973 (Box 12)
    - Chekhov Studio and Centre, x (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Children's theatre, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Children's World, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Circle Rep, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Clippings featuring or about Beatrice Straight, 1969-1989 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Miscellaneous clippings, 1967-1987 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - "A World of Theater: Martha Coigney, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Connecticut Arts Awards, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - The Conservancy, n. d. (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Peter W. Cookson, Jr., [1978] (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Cornell University, 1977, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Cornish School of Allied Arts, 1975, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Dartington College of the Arts I: educational philosophy, 1967-1989, n. d. (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Dartington College of the Arts II: publications, 1975-1989 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Dartington College of the Arts III: brief sketches of individuals (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Dartington: play review (play not named), n. d. (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Death: A Concept Reborn, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Democratic Party, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - East Indies Farm (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Eastside Playhouse, n. d. (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Elmhirst, Dorothy (Whitney Straight), and Michael Chekhov, 1939, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Elmhirst, Dorothy, talk at Dartington, n. d. (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Emmy Awards, [1978] (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Ensemble Studio Theatre, 1988/1989 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Equity-League Welfare Trust Fund, [1976] (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Family Weekly, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Fashion/Decorating, 1970-1982 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Folie Douce, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Golden Bough Theatre, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - HB Playwrights Foundation, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - George Ray Hill, 1989-1990 (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Hoboken Theater Company, Inc., 1989-1990 (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - Inner City Cultural Center: Neworld, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - Institute for Advanced Studies in Theatre Arts (IASTA), 1977, n. d. (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - International Theatre Institute of the United States, Inc., 1977-1989 (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - "Journey to Ka Mountain," by Basil Langton, n. d. (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Franklyn Lenthall, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - Lincoln Square Neighborhood Center, n. d. (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - Love Theatre, n. d. (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - Manhattan Theatre Club, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 40)
    - Media Center for Children, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 41)
    - Richard Morse Mime Theatre, 1976-1979 (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - Musicals of the 1930s, n. d. (Box 3, Folder 43)
    - National Repertory Theatre, n. d. (Box 3, Folder 44)
    - The New Dramatists, 1977, 1990, n. d. (Box 3, Folder 45)
    - New Manufactory, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 46)
    - New Marlborough Historical Society, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 47)
    - The New School, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 48)
    - New York State Department of Agriculture and Markets, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 49)
    - Northwood Institute, n. d. (Box 3, Folder 50)
    - Jay O'Callahan, n. d. (Box 3, Folder 51)
    - Old Vic, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 52)
    - Eugene O'Neill Memorial Theater Center, Inc., 1981, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 53)
    - Oscars, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 54)
    - "'Our Town' Remembered," Thomas Coley, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 55)
    - Antoinette Perry Awards, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 56)
    - Poetic Philosophy, n. d. (Box 3, Folder 57)
    - Poetry: clippings, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 58)
    - Poetry: Elizabeth B. and Robert Browning (Box 3, Folder 59)
    - Poetry: T. S. Eliot, [post-1951] (Box 3, Folder 60)
    - Poetry: Thomas Hardy, n. d. (Box 3, Folder 61)
    - Poetry: Edna St. Vincent Millay, n. d. (Box 3, Folder 62)
    - Poetry: selected poets, n. d. (Box 3, Folder 63)
    - Poetry: selected poets, n. d. (Box 7, Folder 4-5)
    - Poetry: Victorian poets, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 64)
    - "Poets as Prophets: Living at the Edge of Consciousness", n. d. (Box 3, Folder 65)
    - "Press Cuttings" and "The Musical Cure" (Box 3, Folder 66)
    - Dory Previn, n. d. (Box 3, Folder 67)
    - Reader's Repertory Company, n. d. (Box 3, Folder 68)
    - Roundabout Theatre, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 69)
    - "Saturday Theatre for Children", 1990 (Box 3, Folder 70)
    - Shakespeare & Company, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 71)
    - Shakespeare's Globe, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 72)
    - Ravi Shankar, n. d. (Box 3, Folder 73)
    - Uday Shankar [see also correspondence Mohan Khokar], 1977, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 74)
    - Sharon Playhouse, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 75)
    - Stanislavsky, 1964, n. d. (Box 3, Folder 76)
    - Arnold Sundgaard (Box 3, Folder 77)
    - "Eve" [Symington], 1973 (Box 3, Folder 78)
    - Theatre clippings, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 79)
    - Theatre Communications Group, 1989-90 (Box 3, Folder 80)
    - Theatre Hall of Fame, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 81)
    - Theatre Institute at Storm King, n. d. (Box 3, Folder 82)
    - Theatre of the Open Eye, n. d. (Box 3, Folder 83)
    - Theatreworks I, 1986-1989 (Box 3, Folder 84)
    - Theatreworks II, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 85)
    - Theatreworks III, 1990-1991 (Box 3, Folder 86)
    - "A Visit From St. Nicholas," Clement Moore [facsimile], [1849] (Box 3, Folder 87)
    - Edith Wharton and the Mount (Box 3, Folder 88)
    - Joan White English Theatre School, n. d. (Box 3, Folder 89)
    - Getrude Vanderbilt Whitney (Box 3, Folder 90)
    - William C. Whitney Foundation, 1970-1977 (Box 3, Folder 91)
    - Whitney Award, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 92)
    - Women in Foundations, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Michael Young, n. d. (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Publicity materials [(B)=Beatrice participated, (P)=Peter Cookson participated
    - "All My Sons," by Arthur Miller: clippings, programs, reviews (B), 1974 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - "Andros Targets": clipping (B), [1977] (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - "Beacon Hill": clippings, review, Irish dialect instructions (B), 1975-1978 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - "Bicentennial Minutes": press release (B), 1976 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - "Bloodline": shooting schedule, cast list, unit list, reviews, clippings (B), 1978-1979 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - "Can Can": program, clippings, reviews (P), 1953 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - "Checkout": program, clipping, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - "The Crucible": clipping (B), [1971] (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - "Dain Curse": call sheets, clippings, reviews (B), 1977-1978 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - "Don't Ride the Clutch": broadside, n. d. (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - "Eastward in Eden": clipping (B), n. d. (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - "Endless Love": clipping (B), [1981] (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - An Evening With Beatrice Straight (Houston, Texas): clipping, press release (B), 1988 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - "Everything in the Garden": program (B), [1967] (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - "Faces of Woman in Opera": program (B), 1988 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - "Festival Thirteen": full-page advertisement, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - "The Formula": full-page advertisement, review, clippings (B), 1980 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - "The Formula": broadside, [1980] (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - "Four Winds": publicity pamphlet, clippings, reviews (P), 1957 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - "Frozen Man," J. D. Feigelson (B), 1957 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - "The Garden Party": press release (B), 1985 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - "Ghosts": press release, program, program notes, clippings, leaflet, reviews, "Ghost Story," by Rabindranath Tagore (B), 1973 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - "Gideon": program, 1962 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - "The Girl of the Golden West": clippings, reviews (P), 1957 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - "The Glass Menagerie": clippings, 2 programs (B), 1980 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - "The Grand Tour": clippings (B), 1951 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - "Hamlet": program, clipping (B), 1979 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - "The Heiress": program (B), [1948] (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - "Henry V": program, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - "Ichabod": broadside, n. d. (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - "The Innocents": programs, clippings, reviews (B), 1950 (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - "Killer on Board": press release, clipping (B), 1977 (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - "King Lear": clipping (B), 1953 (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - "King's Crossing": clippings (B), 1981-1982 (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - "Lend Me a Tenor": program, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - "Light Up The Sky": program, clipping (B), 1968 (Box 4, Folder 37)
    - "Lila's Island": story, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 38)
    - "The Lion in Winter": programs, review, clipping (B), 1966, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 39)
    - "The Lion in Winter": broadside (B), [1976] (Map-case Folder 4)
    - "A Little Night Music": program, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 40)
    - "MacBeth": sleep walking speech (B), n. d. (Box 4, Folder 41)
    - Maine Theatre Arts Festival: program (B), n. d. (Box 4, Folder 42)
    - March of Dimes Gala: clippings (B), 1986 (Box 4, Folder 43)
    - Marie R: broadside (B), 1972 (Map-case Folder 4)
    - "Mary Stuart": program, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 44)
    - "Message for Margaret": clippings (P), n. d. (Box 4, Folder 45)
    - Metropolitan Museum of Art: clippings re answering machine message recorded by B. Straight (B), 1978 (Box 4, Folder 46)
    - "Network": clippings, reviews, press release, academy award notices (B), 1977 (Box 4, Folder 47)
    - "Night of 100 Stars": full-page advertisement (B), 1977 (Box 4, Folder 48)
    - "Old Times": contact sheet for theatre, program, clippings, reviews (B), 1977 (Box 4, Folder 49)
    - "Old Times": broadside (B), [1977] (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - "The Palace at 4 A. M.": program, clippings, reviews (B), 1972 (Box 4, Folder 50)
    - "Patterns": reviews, clippings (B), 1955-1956 (Box 4, Folder 51)
    - "People Like Us": staff and crew lists, reviews (B), 1990 (Box 4, Folder 52)
    - "Phèdre": show cards, programs, notes, clippings, reviews (B), 1965-1966 (Box 4, Folder 53)
    - "Playboy of the Western World": clipping, Theatre Arts, 9/1946 (2 copies) (B) (Box 4, Folder 54)
    - "Playboy of the Western World": clipping (B), 1946 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - "Poltergeist": program, clippings, reviews (B), 1982 (Box 4, Folder 55)
    - "Poor Bitos": clippings, reviews, 1982 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - "Private Eye": clipping (B), 1977 (Box 4, Folder 56)
    - "The Promise": cast list, staff list, list of contact people, mailing lists, board of directors list, production notes, clippings, reviews (B), 1977-1979 (Box 4, Folder 57)
    - "The Right Honourable Gentleman": list of actors, programs, clippings, reviews, broadsides, box office statements (B), 1966, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 58)
    - "The Right Honourable Gentleman": set plans, broadside, sheet musicc (B), [1971] (Map-case Folder 2)
    - "Robert Kennedy and His Times": printed sheets from CBS, call sheets, production notes and schedules (B), 1983-1984 (Box 4, Folder 59)
    - Eleanor Roosevelt Monument Fund Benefit: invitation, portrait of E. R., 1987 (Box 4, Folder 60)
    - "Second Chance": call sheets, notes from cast and staff, printed images, production schedules (B), 1983 (Box 4, Folder 61)
    - "Shadows Tremble" (Playhouse 90): press releases (B), n. d. (Box 4, Folder 62)
    - "Sing Me No Lullaby": program (B), 1954 (Box 4, Folder 63)
    - "Stanley,": clipping (B), 1970 (Box 4, Folder 64)